Guide to the African Americans in Film Collection, 1919-2000 RL.00019
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Malcolm X, 1972 (Box 3)
  Press book; "Feature-length documentary about the life of Malcolm X, given a very limited release by Warner Brothers, all materials from this film are extremely hard to find."
- Malcolm X, 1992 (Box 3)
  Promotional book; "Directed by Spike Lee. Deluxe special illustrated promotional book on the film, printed in small edition, profusely and richly illustrated."
- Man and Boy, 1971 (Oversize-folder 26)
- Man and Boy, 1971 (Oversize-folder 26)
- Man Friday, 1975 (Box 3)
  Ad Supplement; "With special promotion for Black audiences."
- Man, The, 1972 (Box 3)
  Press book; Starring James Earl Jones. "The first Black President of the United States. First they swore him in. Then they swore to get him."
- Man, The, 1972 (Oversize-folder 7)
- Mandingo, 1975 (Box 3)
  Starring Ken Norton and Brenda Sykes.
- Mark of the Hawk, The, 1957 (Box 3)
  Starring Sidney Poitier, Eartha Kitt, and Juano Hernandez.
- Marked For Death, 1990 (Box 3)
  Starring Basil Wallace.
- Maurie, 1973 (Oversize-folder 27)
- McMasters, The, 1969 (Box 3)
  Starring Brock Peters.
- McMasters, The, 1969 (Box 3)
- Mean Mother, 1973 (Box 3)
  Starring Clifton Brown.
- Melinda, 1972 (Oversize-folder 8)
- Men in Black, 1997 (Box 3)
  Japanese promotional brochure; Starring Will Smith.
- Mission Impossible, 1996 (Box 3)
  Screening program; Starring Ving Rhames.
- Monkey Hustle, 1976 (Box 5)
- Monkey Hustle, 1975 (Oversize-folder 27)
  poster; minor bleed-thru of distributor stamp
- Mr. Mean, 1977 (Oversize-folder 27)
- Muthers, The, 1976 (Box 3)
  Starring Jeanne Bell and Jayne Kennedy.
- Naked Gun 2 1/2, 1991 (Box 3)
  British press book; Starring O.J. Simpson.
- Naked Prey, The, 1966 (Box 3)
  Starring Ken Gampu.
- Naked Prey, The, 1966 (Box 3)
  British campaign book
- Naked Prey, The, 1966 (Box 3)
  Promotional pamphlet
- New Jack City, 1991 (Box 3)
  Japanese promotional brochure; Starring Wesley Snipes.
- Norman ... Is That You?, 1976 (Box 5)
- Norman, Is That You?, 1976 (Oversize-folder 27)
- Nothing But a Man, 1964 (Box 5)
- Obsessed One, The, 1974 (Oversize-folder 8)
- On the Block, 1990 (Oversize-folder 27)
- On the Right Track, 1981 (Oversize-folder 28)
- One Down, Two to Go, 1982 (Oversize-folder 28)
  poster; rippled lower border
- One More Time, 1970 (Box 3)
  Press book; Starring Sammy Davis, Jr.
- Organization, The, 1971 (Box 3)
- Organization, The, 1971 (Box 5)
- Paris Blues, 1961 (Box 3)
  Press book; Starring Sidney Poitier and Diahann Carroll.
- Part 2 Sounder, 1976 (Oversize-folder 28)
- Penitentiary, 1979 (Box 5)
- Penitentiary, 1979 (Oversize-folder 28)
- Penitentiary II, 1982 (Oversize-folder 28)
  poster; rippling at folds from folding
- Piece of the Action, A, 1977 (Box 5)
- Piece of the Action, A, 1977 (Oversize-folder 8)
- Pipe Dreams (Style A), 1976 (Oversize-folder 8)
- Pipe Dreams, 1976 (Box 5)
- Police Academy, 1984 (Box 3)
  British press book; Strring Michael Winslow and Bubba Smith.
- Pressure Point, 1962 (Tube 1)
- Pressure Point, 1962 (Box 3)
- Quadroon, 1972 (Box 3)
- Quadroon, 1972 (Box 3)
- Rainbow Bridge, 1972 (Box 3)
  Press book; Starring Jimi Hendrix.
- Raisin in the Sun, A, 1961 (Box 5)
- Regeneration, 1923 (Box 3)
  "Romance in Southern Seas featuring Stella Mayo, Sensational Colored Screen Beauty. All-Colored Cast, contains a detailed list of proposed upcoming production and text emphasizing that Norman is the only Company making Colored Pictures that owns and operates its own studio and laboratory."
- Return of Mandy's Husband, 1948 (Box 5)
  Lobby cards (6); "Group of six half-tone lobby cards. 11x14 inches; some small stains here and there. Florida: Toddy Films, 1948. One of a series of Toddy Films' comedies featuring Mantan Moreland."
- Riot, 1969 (Box 3)
- Riot, 1969 (Box 3)
  Promotional booklet The Prison Record
- Robin and the 7 Hoods, 1964 (Box 3)
  Press book; "Sammy Davis Jr. in one of the famous Rat Pack films with Frank Sinatra, Dean Martin, et al." Bogle II, p. 214-5: On the surface the clan pictures were egalitarian affairs; underneath they rotted from white patronizing and hypocrisy.
- Rock Baby, Rock It, 1957 (Box 3)
  "B-movie rock musical showcased calypso group the Five Stars."
- Rock Baby, Rock It, 1957 (Box 3)
- Rocky III, 1982 (Box 3)
- Sam Whiskey, 1969 (Box 4)
  Press book; Starring Ossie Davis.
- Sapphire, 1959 (Box 4)
  "Rare film about Afro-British life, a mystery about a young woman attempting to pass."
- Savage, 1973 (Box 5)
- Savage, 1973 (Oversize-folder 8)
- Save the Children, 1973 (Oversize-folder 29)
- Save the Children, 1973 (Box 4)
  Press book; Featuring Jesse Jackson, Sammy Davis Jr., the Chi-Lites, Nancy Wilson, and the Temptations. "Concert film from the 1972 Operation PUSH exposition in Chicago, interspersed with documentary footage of the period."
- Save the Children, 1973 (Box 4)
  Advertising sheets
- Scalphunters, The, 1968 (Box 4)
  Advertising supplement (#2)
- Scott Joplin, 1977 (Oversize-folder 9)
- Scream, Blacula, Scream, 1973 (Oversize-folder 29)
- Scream, Blacula, Scream, 1973 (Box 4)
- Scream, Blacula, Scream, 1973 (Box 4)
  Starring William Marshall.
- Seizure, 1974 (Box 4)
  Press book; Starring Henry Baker.
- Shaft, 1971 (Oversize-folder 29)
- Shaft in Africa, 1973 (Box 4)
- Shaft, 1971 (Box 4)
  Press book; "One of the legendary films which launched the Blaxploitation film cycle of the 1970s."
- Shaft's Big Score!, 1972 (Box 4)
  Press book; "Director Gordon Parks and Richard Roundtree teamed up again for this first sequel."
- Shaft's Big Score!, 1972 (Box 4)
  Press book
- She's Too Mean for Me, 1948 (Oversize-folder 29)
- Shock Corridor, 1963 (Box 4)
- Silver Streak, 1976 (Box 4)
  Press book; "The first of a very successful series of comedies pairing Richard Pryor and Gene Wilder."
- Six Thousand Dollar N*gger, 1978 (Oversize-folder 30)
  poster; undersized, extra folds
- Skin Game, 1971 (Box 4)
  Press book; Starring Lou Gossett, Jr.
- Slammer, 1977 (Oversize-folder 30)
- Slams, The, 1973 (Box 4)
  Press book; Starring Jim Brown and Judy Pace.
- Slams, The, 1973 (Oversize-folder 10)
- Slaughter, 1972 (Box 5)
- Slaughter, 1972 (Oversize-folder 9)
- Slaughter's Big Rip-Off, 1973 (Box 4)
  Starring Jim Brown and Brock Peters.
- Slaves, The, 1969 (Box 4)
  Starring Dionne Warwick and Ossie Davis. "Official entry 1969 Cannes Film Festival."
- Slender Thread, The, 1965 (Box 4)
- Solomon King, 1974 (Box 5)
- Some Kind of Hero, 1982 (Oversize-folder 30)
- Soul of N*gger Charley, 1973 (Oversize-folder 30)
  poster; smudge in right border
- Soul of Nigger Charley, 1973 (Box 4)
  Press book; Starring Fred Williamson.
- Soul of Nigger Charley, 1973 (Box 4)
- Soul of Nigger Charley, 1973 (Oversize-folder 9)
- Soul Soldier, 1970 (Box 4)
  "Very early entry in the Blaxploitation cycle starring athlete Rafer Johnson."
- Soul Soldier, 1970 (Oversize-folder 9)
- Soul to Soul, 1971 (Oversize-folder 30)
- Soul to Soul, 1971 (Box 4)
  Press book; Starring Roberta Flack and Wilson Pickett.
- Sounder, 1972 (Box 5)
- Sparkle, 1976 (Box 4)
  Starring Irene Cara and Lonette McKee.
- Sparkle, 1976 (Oversize-folder 9)
- Sparkle, 1976 (Oversize-folder 31)
- Split, The, 1968 (Box 4)
  Campaign book; Starring Jim Brown and Diahann Carroll.
- Spook Who Sat by the Door, The, 1973 (Box 5)
- St. Louis Blues, 1958 (Box 4)
  Theatre program; Starring Eartha Kitt, Nat King Cole, Ruby Dee, Ella Fitzgerald, Cab Calloway, Pearl Bailey, and Mahalia Jackson. "Theatre program from Germany, with an elegant photomontage of images from the film."
- Steely Brown, 1976 (Oversize-folder 31)
- Stormy Weather, 1943 (Box 4)
  Souvenir program; "Famous wartime musical which made use of an astonishing virtual who's who of top African-American talents. Lena Horne. Fats Waller. The Nicholas Brothers. Cab Calloway. Bill Robinson. All promotional materials from this film are extremely scarce. This is a nicely illustrated souvenir program from Denmark."
- Story of a Three-Day Pass, 1968 (Box 5)
- Straight out of Brooklyn, 1991 (Oversize-folder 31)
- Stud Brown, 1974 (Oversize-folder 31)
- Sugar Hill, 1974 (Box 4)
  Starring Marki Bey.
- Sugar Hill, 1974 (Oversize-folder 10)
- Super Fly T.N.T., 1973 (Tube 1)
- Super Fly T.N.T., 1973 (Box 4)
  Press book; Starring Ron O'Neal.
- Super Fly T.N.T., 1973 (Box 4)
- Super Fly, 1972 (Box 4)
- Superfly T.N.T., 1973 (Oversize-folder 10)
- Swashbuckler, 1976 (Box 4)
- Sweet Jesus Preacher Man, 1973 (Box 4)
  Press book; Starring Roger E. Mosely.
- Sweet Jesus Preacher Man, 1973 (Oversize-folder 31)
- Sweet Sweetback's Baadasssss Song, 1971 (Box 4)
  Press book; "Melvin Van Peebles (director). [This is an extremely rare press book, all original materials from this film seem to have vanished a long time ago.]"
- Take a Giant Step, 1959 (Oversize-folder 32)
  poster; Canadian ink censor stamp
- Take a Hard Ride, 1975 (Box 5)
- Take A Hard Ride, 1975 (Box 4)
- Take, The, 1974 (Box 5)
- Take, The, 1974 (Oversize-folder 32)
- Tamango, 1958 (Box 5)
  lobby cards
- Teenage Millionaire, 1962 (Box 4)
  Press book; Starring Jackie Wilson and Chubby Checker.
- That Man Bolt, 1973 (Box 4)
- That Man Bolt, 1973 (Box 4)
- That Man Bolt, 1973 (Oversize-folder 10)
- That's the Way of the World, 1975 (Box 4)
  Press book; Starring the group Earth, Wind, and Fire.
- The River Niger, 1976 (Oversize-folder 29)
  poster; NSS stamp at bottom
- They Call Me Mister Tibbs, 1970 (Oversize-folder 32)
- They Call Me Mister Tibbs, 1970 (Box 4)
- Thing with Two Heads, The, 1972 (Box 5)
- Things Fall Apart, 1974 (Oversize-folder 32)
- Thomasine and Bushrod, 1974 (Oversize-folder 10)
- Three the Hard Way, 1974 (Box 4)
  Starring Jim Brown, Fred Williamson, and Jim Kelly. Directed by Gordon Parks, Jr.
- Three Tough Guys, 1974 (Box 5)
- Three Tough Guys, 1974 (Oversize-folder 32)
- Thunder over Sangoland, 1955 (Oversize-folder 32)
  poster; image of James Edwards
- Tick... Tick... Tick..., 1970 (Box 4)
  Starring Jim Brown. [A small area of blank margin to one leaf is missing, with no content affected].
- Tick... Tick... Tick..., 1970 (Oversize-folder 11)
- To Kill A Mockingbird, 1967 (Box 4)
  1967 reissue of 1962 film; Starring Brock Peters. "Reissue on a double bill with, of all the possible unlikely choices, a Doris Day comedy."
- To Sir, With Love, 1966 (Box 4)
- To Sir, With Love, 1966 (Box 4)
  Advertising press book insert; "Multiple-run and hold over advertising press book insert."
- Together Brothers, 1974 (Box 5)
- Together Brothers, 1974 (Oversize-folder 11)
- Top of the Heap, 1972 (Box 4)
  Starring Christopher St. John (also producer, writer, and director). Early entry in the Blaxploitation cycle. Bogle II, p. 241.
- Top of the Heap, 1972 (Oversize-folder 11)
- Topaz, 1969 (Box 4)
  Advertising booklet; Starring Roscoe Lee Browne
- Topaz, 1969 (Box 4)
- Tough, 1974 (Oversize-folder 11)
- Towering Inferno, The, 1974 (Box 4)
  Press book; Starring O.J. Simpson.
- Toy, The, 1982 (Box 4)
  Special advertising printout
- Trick Baby, 1973 (Box 6)
- Trick Baby, 1972 (Oversize-folder 11)
- Trouble Man, 1972 (Box 5)
- Trouble Man, 1972 (Box 4)
  Starring Robert Hooks and Paula Kelly.
- Trouble Man, 1972 (Oversize-folder 12)
- Truck Turner, 1974 (Box 4)
  Starring Isaac Hayes.
- Truck Turner, 1974 (Box 4)
  Promotional newsletter; Starring Isaac Hayes. "Special promotional piece in the form of a newsletter, International Bail Bond News."
- Truck Turner, 1974 (Box 4)
  Press book; "Special press book for a double-bill release with Foxy Brown (1974)."
- Twilight Zone-The Movie, 1983 (Box 4)
  British campaign book; Starring Scatman Crothers.
- Two Gentlemen Sharing, 1969 (Box 4)
  Starring Hal Frederick and Esther Anderson. "Unusual but sensationally-treated story of mixed race couples."
- Up Tight, 1968 (Oversize-folder 12)
- Uptight!, 1968 (Box 4)
  Starring Ruby Dee and Roscoe Lee Browne.
- Uptown Saturday Night, 1974 (Box 5)
- Uptown Saturday Night, 1974 (Oversize-folder 33)
- Uptown Saturday Night, 1974 (Oversize-folder 12)
- Warm December, A, 1973 (Box 4)
- Warm December, 1973 (Oversize-folder 33)
- Watermelon Man, 1970 (Box 4)
- Watermelon Man, 1970 (Oversize-folder 12)
- Watusi, 1959 (Box 4)
  Starring Rex Ingram.
- Watusi, 1959 (Box 4)
  Promotional booklet
- Welcome Home, Brother Charles, 1975 (Oversize-folder 12)
- Which Way Is Up?, 1977 (Box 6)
- Willie Dynamite, 1974 (Box 6)
- Willie Dynamite, 1974 (Oversize-folder 33)
- Winterhawk, 1976 (Box 4)
  Starring Woody Strode.
- Woodstock, 1970 (Box 4)
  "Legendary rock musical showcases Sly and the Family Stone, Richie Havens, and, of course, Jimi Hendrix."
- World, The Flesh and the Devil, The, 1959 (Box 4)
  Press book; Starring Harry Belafonte. "Science-fiction film in which Belafonte is one of only three survivors of a nuclear holocaust, produced by Belafonte."
- World's Greatest Athlete, The, 1973 (Box 4)
- Wusa, 1970 (Box 4)
  Starring Moses Gunn.
- Youngblood, 1978 (Oversize-folder 33)
- Zebra Killer, 1974 (Oversize-folder 33)
- Zircon, 1920 (Box 4)
  "Flyer for unproduced film serial of the 1920s featuring 15 chapters. Also features advertisements for films "Regeneration," "The Crimson Skull," "Green Eyed Monster," and "The Bull Dogger.""